From a high level perspective,
从高层次来看
you've been able to see that limiting CPU instructions can make your code run faster.
你已经看到了限制 CPU 指令可以使你的代码运行得更快
As humans, we think about interacting with a computer in
作为人类 我们考虑采用 C++ 等编程语言
terms of a programming language like C++.
与电脑进行互动
However, computers only understand instructions in binary.
然而 计算机只能理解二进制指令
So everything you write will be seen by the computer as a series of zeros and ones.
所以你写的所有东西都会被计算机看成是一连串的 0 和 1
Let's dive a little deeper into how the computer
让我们深入了解一下电脑
uses binary to store information in memory.
如何使用二进制在内存中存储信息
Understanding how your C++ program stores information can help you
了解你的 C++ 程序如何存储信息可以帮助你
avoid unnecessary access to memory which will waste valuable CPU cycles.
避免不必要的内存访问 从而避免浪费宝贵的 CPU 周期
Let's think about how you could represent a variable in binary.
让我们思考一下如何用二进制表示一个变量
Binary relies on powers of two to describe
二进制采用二次幂来描述
a value with the least significant digit usually on the right.
一个通常将最低有效位数放在右边的值
For each position in the binary representation,
对于二进制表示中的每个位置
you take the binary value of one or zero and multiply it by
你取一个 1 或 0 的二进制值并乘以
the power of two associated with that position and using zero-based numbering.
与该位置相关的二次幂并使用基于零的编号
Finally, you add the results together to get the decimal value.
最后 将结果加在一起得到十进制值
Now let's go through a few examples by looking at
现在我们来看几个例子
the binary representation of the numbers one through five.
看看数字 1 到 5 的二进制表示
The decimal number zero is also zero in binary.
十进制数 0 的二进制表示仍然是 0
To figure this out, you take zero times two_to_the_power_of_zero which equals zero.
为了解决这个问题 你采用 0 乘以 2 的零次幂 算出来等于 0
The decimal number one is one in binary.
十进制数 1 的二进制表示是 1
You can see this because one times two_to_the_power_of_zero equals one.
因为 1 乘以 2 的零次幂 等于 1
One, zero in binary equals the decimal number two.
二进制数 10 等于十进制数 2
Now you're going to need it two to the first power as well.
你也需要乘以 2 的一次幂
This is because one times two to the first power
因为 1 乘以 2 的一次幂
plus one times two to_the_zeroth_power equals two.
加上 0 乘以 2 的零次幂 等于 2
Following the same rules, one,
采用相同的规则 二进制数 11
one in binary is three in decimal.
等于 十进制数 3
This is because one times
因为 1 乘以
two_to_the_first_power plus one times two_to_the_zeroth_power equals three.
2的一次幂 加上 1 乘以 2 的零次幂 等于 3
One, zero, zero in binary is four in decimal.
二进制数 100 等于十进制数 4
One times two_to_the_second_power plus zero times
1 乘以 2 的二次幂 加上 0 乘以
two_to_the_first_power plus zero times two_to_the_zeroth_power equals four.
2 的一次幂 加上  0 乘以  2 的零次幂  等于 4
And finally, one, zero, one is five in decimal.
最后 二进制数 101 等于十进制数 5
Following the same process,
以此类推
you would calculate one times two_to_the_power_of_two plus zero times
1 乘以 乘以 2 的二次幂 加上 0 乘以
two_to_the_power_of_one plus one times two_to_the_power_of_zero which equals five.
2 的一次幂 加上 1 乘以  2 的零次幂  等于 5
You can represent any decimal digit using binary.
你可以采用二进制数表示任何十进制数
For example, the number 25 would be one,
例如 十进制数 25 在二进制数中 将表示为
And here, you can see how to calculate this to get that result.
在这里 你能看到如何计算出这个结果
The computer represents all variables in binary, not just integers.
计算机以二进制表示所有变量 而不仅仅只能表示整数
This means, even characters and floating point numbers are represented in binary.
这意味着即使是字符和浮点数都可以采用二进制表示
But your computer can't store an arbitrary amount of zeros and ones at a time.
但是 你的计算机不能一次存储任意数量的 0 和 1
Instead, memory is stored in collections of
相反 内存是存储在八个二进制数字中
eight binary digits where each digit is called a bit.
其中 每个数字被称为一个位
You can think of your computer's memory in terms of these eight-bit slots,
你可以根据这些 8 位二进制来考虑计算机的内存
and each eight-bit slot is called one byte.
而每个 8 位二进制称为一个字节
In C++, the smallest variable would be an eight-bit or one-byte character.
在 C++ 中 最小的变量为 8 位二进制 或者说 一个字节
A 16-bit integer has two bytes and a 32-bit integer uses four bytes.
一个 16 位整数有两个字节 一个 32 位整数采用四个字节
A float also uses four bytes.
一个浮点数 也采用 四个字节 进行存放
In C++, your variables will always
在 C++ 中 变量通常采用
use the amount of memory specified by the variable type.
变量类型指定的内存量
For example, the number 3,378 only needs 12 bits.
例如 数字 3,378 只需要 12 个字节存储
But represented as a 16-bit integer,
不过却表示为一个 16 字节整数
it will need two bytes with extra zeros padded to the left.
那么需要采用零在左侧填充两个字节
And as a 32-bit integer,
作为一个 32 字节整数
it will have much more zero padding which
它需要更多零进行填充
basically means the most significant bits will be zero.
基本上意味着最重要的位将是零
In C++, you can declare a 16,
在 C++ 中 你可以宣告一个 16 字节
32, or even a 64-bit integer.
32 字节 或者甚至是一个 64 字节
All this means is that the integer is using two,
所有这些都意味着这个整数正采用两个
four, or eight bytes of memory.
四个 或者八个字节内存
You can start to appreciate how the number of bits available becomes a constraint.
你可以开始理解这些可用的字节数如何变成了一种约束
If an integer can only use 32 bits,
如果一个整数只能使用 32 字节
then the maximum value would have all bits equal to one.
那么其最大值将是所有等于 1 的字节数
The decimal equivalent is
十进制等值是
4,294,967,295 and that number
4,294,967,295 这个数字
is the maximum value that a 32-bit integer can store,
是 32 字节整数能够存储的最大值
and is even less if you're using signed numbers.
并且如果你正在使用带符号数 这个值甚至更小
Now that you have an understanding of how to represent variables in binary,
现在你已经理解了如何用二进制表示变量
you'll learn what C++ does to store and extract this information.
你将学习 C++ 如何存储和提取这些信息
Remember that part of optimizing your code involves
请记住 优化你的代码的一部分会
limiting the number of times your program reads and writes to memory.
牵涉到限制你的程序读写内存的次数
You'll need some insight into when and why these read and write operations happen.
你需要了解何时以及为什么会发生这些读取和写入操作